我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的
But secretly, with the help of my friends
朋友们的帮助下
at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪
I fight crime
寻找跟我一样的超能力者
and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present.
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
And now our world is more dangerous than ever,
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
"蝉"是谁
Who's Cicada?
"蝉"
是谁
你永远捉不到他
You'll never catch him.
这位是歇洛克
This is Sherloque.
他是多元宇宙中最棒的侦探
He's the greatest detective in all the multiverse.
我也是名侦探
I'm a detective as well.
我是来帮你们抓凶手的
I'm here to catch your killer.
所以我们要对付有超能力的开膛手杰克
So we're dealing with a meta-human Jack the Ripper.
在我们那的历史里
In my history,
他从来没有杀过路霸和方块
he never killed Gridlock or Block.
那些是完全不同的受害者
They're completely different victims.
-他出现早了  -因为时间线变了
- He's early. - Because the timeline changed.
因为我
Because of me.
大悟之道当晚
各位  这太疯狂了
Guys, this is mad crazy!
空中有好多火球
There are, like, fireballs in the sky!
天呐
Holy--
我要看清楚些
I'm gonna get a better look.
他在那  这要起大火
There he is! This is gonna be lit.
等下  有两个
Wait, there's two of them?
天呐  各位  那是什么
Oh, my God, guys. What was that?
太疯狂了  现在是怎么回事
This is cray! What is going on right now?
是世界末日了吗
Is the world, like, ending right now?
我的手机
Oh, my phone.
你救了我
You just saved my life.
你是第二个极速者
You are the second speedster
刚刚拯救了世界
who just, like, saved the world.
我能  我能拍张
Can I just get a-- can I just get a...
自拍吗
selfie.
我去
What the...
*我在晨曦中回家*
*I come home in the morning light*
*我妈妈说  你什么时候才好好生活*
*My mother says, "When you gonna live your life right?"*
*亲爱的妈妈  我们又不是幸运儿*
*Oh, Mother dear, we're not the fortunate ones*
*女孩子们都想玩得开心*
*And girls, they wanna have fun*
*女孩子都想*
*Oh, girls just wanna have*
*那是她们真正想要的*
*That's all they really want*
《女孩们都想玩得开心》
*开心*
*Some fun*
*当工作日结束*
*When the working day is done*
《女孩们都想玩得开心》
对不起
Sorry.
-你在干嘛  -没什么  接着睡吧
- What are you doing? - Uh, nothing. Go back to bed.
我在做早餐
I'm just making some breakfast.
说得好像闻到吉斯特咖啡
Like I could go to sleep
我还能睡着一样
after the smell of Jitters coffee.
看来你的厨艺还是一如既往
So, uh, I see you still know your way around the kitchen.
怎么了
What's happening?
-亲爱的  -早
- Uh, hey, babe. - Good morning.
我在想
Um, I, um, was thinking
我们可以一起吃个早餐
that we could have breakfast together.
对吧  就像一家人一样
Right? Like a family.
-不错  -是的
- I love it. - Yeah.
你  嗨
Do you--Hi.
你需要帮忙吗
Do you need any help?
不不  你们坐着就好
No, no. You guys just sit.
好的
Okay.
我们吃什么呢
What...do we have here?
薄煎饼  正如你所见
Well, these are pancakes, as you can see,
但我把它们做成了闪电的样子
but I made them into little lightning bolts.
面糊有点不听话
Well, the batter kind of got away from me,
但你看这个锯齿形
but you see the little zigzag--
不不  我完全能看出来
No, no, no. Yeah, yeah. I totally see it, yeah.
是的
Yeah.
你在做什么啊
What are--what are you doing?
我在搜集你在不同时间里
Uh, I am just getting evidence
做的煎饼都一样丑的证据
that you make lumpy pancakes in every time period.
我们试下吧
Let's try it out.
有点糙  但很好吃
Mmm. Lumpy, but delicious.
是吗  谢谢亲爱的
Yeah? Oh, thanks, babe.
不好意思  你什么时候买的手机
I'm sorry, um, when did you-- when did you get a phone?
爸爸几天前给我买的
Uh, Dad got it for me a couple days ago.
诺拉提议的  我觉得是个好主意
Nora suggested it. I mean, I thought it was a great idea.
我们经常出入尖端科研实验室  所以我
We're always in and out of S.T.A.R. Labs, so I just--
这样方便短信或电话联系
you know, it'd be easier to text and call.
对
Yeah.
这很有道理
Yeah, that totally makes sense.
你们有没有很兴奋啊
You guys excited to cheer me on
要去慈善垒球赛给我加油
at the charity softball game?
垒球  酷炫
Softball, schway.
我只希望今年不再困在右外场
I just hope I don't get stuck in right field this year.
你已经把号码告诉别人了
You, uh, gave your number out already?
对  就给了小队成员和歇洛克
Yeah, just to the team and Sherloque.
这个短信我觉得就是他发的
Actually, this text message, I think, is from him.
带上自已和你爹玛  赶快来工作
我觉得他不怎么会发短信
I don't think he's much of a texter.
不
No.
他想我们去尖端科研实验室
He, uh, wants us to come to S.T.A.R. Labs.
我要去准备一下
I'm gonna go get ready.
你什么都还没吃呢
You haven't had anything to eat yet.
其实我不太吃早餐
Mm. I'm not really a breakfast person.
我以为她住在这里
You know, I thought having her here,
我们终于有机会沟通
we would finally have a chance to connect,
但似乎每次我们向前迈进半步
but it's like every time we take a half-step forward,
最后却向后倒退六步
we end up taking six steps back.
不要放弃  她会明白的
I-I mean, don't give up. She'll come around.
-我有预感  -嗯
- I have a feeling. - Yeah.
除非我不继续做这么难吃的东西
Well, not if I keep making food like that.
不  这真的很好吃
Hey, no, this really is good.
真的  只是有点
It is. I mean, it's a little, like...
-等等  别说  别说了  -焦  但是
- Wait, wait, stop. Just stop. - Dark, but-- No, it's--
我去给你切香蕉  别吃了
I'm going to make you a banana. It's fine.
你要给我切香蕉吗
You're going to make me a banana?
我去给你切香蕉
I'm going to make you a banana.
谢了
Thanks.
等等  我是叫所有的人来
Wait, no, I asked for everyone.
那个小...
Where is the little, uh-- -
西斯科会在他爸妈家窝着
Cisco is laying low at his parents' house
治疗情伤
while he heals up.
他这样表现得不够勇敢啊
Well, that's not very brave on his part.
下次见到他我会和他好好谈谈
I will have a conversation with him next time I see him.
闪电侠小组
So, Team Flash.
这位多元宇宙的帅气大侦探
How will this handsome, master detective of all the multiverse,
歇洛克·威尔斯
Sherloque Wells,
要如何偿还欠我们的债务
pay off his debt to us...
如何抓到这个杀人狂呢
and catch this homicidal maniac together?
首先我们问问自己几个显而易见的问题
Well, we'll begin by asking ourselves a few obvious questions.
谁是禅
他是如何变成超能力者的
How he became a meta-human?
超能力的表现形式各不相同
Well, power manifestation varies.
粒子加速器
The particle accelerator--
-你们不会打断歇洛克发言吧  -好吧
- I don't think we're interrupting Sherloque, right? - Right.
那好  但是你这个观点说得好  斯诺博士
Sure, but you bring up a good point, Dr. Snow.
目前我们对这个蝉有什么了解
What do we know so far about this Cicada?
我们知道他已经杀了两个人
Well, we know that he's killed two people
还差点杀了第三个
and almost a third.
没错
Exactly right.
如果我能稍微说得再详细一点
If I could gently be a little more specific,
那些不是普通人对吧
not just people, right?
而是超能力者
Meta-humans.
还有  乔说他觉得禅是一位父亲
Also, Joe said he got the feeling that Cicada's a dad.
禅  一位父亲
Right. Cicada... parent.
他的匕首削弱超能力
His dagger dampens powers.
不止是削弱超能力吧
Not just dampens the powers, right?
他能控制匕首
He commands this dagger, right?
就像是如虎添翼  合二为一
It is like an extension of himself.
所以我们得知
So we know...
也许两者是在同一时间获得超能力的
Maybe they acquired their powers at the same time.
非常好  斯诺博士
Yes, very good, Dr. Snow.
同时获得
So, acquired powers...
超能力
together.
那么
So...
这就对了  闪电侠小组
there we are, Team Flash.
非常简单
Very simple.
我们解开这个谜团
We unravel this puzzle,
就有办法追踪禅的下落了
and we have a pathway to tracking Cicada.
棒  或者我们要回答一个更加基本的问题
Cool, or we just answer a much more basic question,
比如他那个奇怪的面具是怎么回事
like what's up with his weird mask?
面具隐藏了他的真实身份
Well, the mask conceals his identity.
-就是这样  -是的
- That's what it's for. - Right.
我的建议是
What I'm suggesting is,
如果我们查出面具的作用
if we find out what the mask is for,
我们就能更快查出他的真实身份了
we'll find out the man underneath much faster.
我抓过禅37次对吧
37 times I have caught Cicada, right?
而这个面具方向都没什么作用对吧
And not once was this mask angle very useful, right?
[法语]
但是你们知道吗
But you know what?
我多帮你们几个小时  我欠你们的钱就越少
The more hours I bill you, the less money I owe you.
如果你们想把时间花在追查面具方向上
So, if you want to spend your hours pursuing the mask angle,
那就请便
well, then be my guest.
好  计划不错
Okay, great. Sounds like a plan.
-我们要走了  还有比赛  -好
- We got to get going. Go to the game. - Yeah, yes.
说得好
Good stuff.
希望你能触底得分
I hope you score a touchdown.
-那是垒球  -投篮得分
- It's softball. - Ah, score a basket.
小长颈鹿
So, baby giraffe...
带路吧  我的朋友
lead on, my friend.
看看这些人
Look at these guys.
他们认为自己比我们打得更好
They think they're so much better than us.
因为他们的确是  巴仔
Because they are, Bar.
没有辛格队长或是我爸
I mean, without Captain Singh or my dad, it's--
-什么  -乔西还没来
- Huh, what? - Jonesy isn't here yet.
罗威尔警探  你怎么看
Hey, Detective Rowell, what do you think?
-也许我去第三垒吧  -右外场  艾伦
- Maybe third base for me? - Right field, Allen.
宝贝  我爱你  但是把三垒
Babe, I love you, but leave the hot corner
留给真正会打垒球的人吧
to someone who can actually field a ball, okay?
-比赛开始  -不是吧
- Play ball! - Come on.
-祝你打出好球  -嗯
- I mean-- Good luck! - Yeah.
-你可以的  -右外场
- You're going to nail it. - Right field.
-天呐  -就在右外场
- Oh, God. - In right field.
虽然不是三垒  各位  开球吧
Not the hot corner, but-- Guys, come on!
安全上垒
Safe!
慈善棒球赛
中城警局  对战  中城消防局
他跑的可真慢
Wow, he really is slow.
乔爷爷告诉了我很多关于
Yeah, Papa Joe told me all the stories
爸爸小时候运动神经有多差的故事
about what an awful athlete Dad was growing up.
相信我  那些都是真的
Well, believe me, they're true.
咱们应该庆幸他在关键时刻
Let's just be grateful that he has coordination
能协调起来
when it counts.
这是什么  诺拉
Hey, what is that, Nora?
这是个超棒的应用  叫斯宾谍网
There is this really great app called Spyn Zone.
只要城里发生了事情  它就会立刻
The push notifications let you know the second
给你发提示信息
anything happens in the city.
和爱瑞丝的网站一样吗
Like Iris' Website?
是啊  类似
Uh, yeah, kind of.
就是比那个更加先进一些
It's just a lot more up to date than that,
而且非常  非常时髦
and it's, like-it's really cool.
这女孩  消息非常灵通
This girl's, like, really in the know.
斯宾塞·扬
对  斯宾塞·扬  我认识她
Yeah, Spencer Young. I know her.
我经常看到她
Yeah, I see her all the time
在吉特斯咖啡店里拿着笔记本干活
working on her laptop at Jitters.
我在中城时报工作的时候
She--she actually was a junior reporter at CCPN
她是那里的初级记者
when I worked there, but...
她没干多久
she didn't last very long.
-为什么   -她只想要出名
- Why not? - Well, she wanted to be famous
自己闯出一番事业
and make a name for herself,
但不在乎过程
but she didn't care how it happened.
我觉得她挺可爱的
Well, I think she's cute.
是  她或许很可爱
Yeah, I mean, she may be cute,
但是她从来没有调查过事件是否真实
but she's never fact-checked a thing a day in her life.
她路子是对的  她应用上的
She's doing something right-she has three times
粉丝比你的博客多三倍  所以...
as many followers on her app as you do on your blogs, so...
我去搞点吃的
I'm going to get something to eat.
-搞什么  艾伦  -哎呀  亲爱的
- Ah, come on, Allen! - Oh, honey.
-塞西尔  怎么了  -感觉不太对
- Cecile? What's wrong? - Something's not right.
有什么不太对
Something's not right.
那是乔西吗
Is that Jonesy?
谁来阻止他
Hey, somebody stop him!
所有人快跑
Everybody move!
-诺拉  -什么
- Nora, hey. - Huh? What?
发生了什么
What happened?
你刚救了大家
You just saved everybody.
炸弹小组已经检查完毕
Bomb squad finished their sweep.
-他们说都安全了  -好吧
- They said it's all clear. - Okay.
诺拉  你怎么知道会发生这种事
Nora, how did you know what was happening?
我不知道
I don't know.
一分钟前我还要去拿吃的
One minute I was going to get food,
接下来我就在球场里和爸爸一起了
and the next I was in the outfield with Dad.
你什么都不记得了吗
And you don't remember anything else?
斯宾谍网警告
新女极速者拯救炸弹危机
是什么
What's that?
斯宾谍网的提醒
A notification from Spyn Zone.
新女极速者拯救炸弹危机
已经出了  可真够快的
Already? That was fast.
艾伦  该现场调查员工作了
Allen, CSI time.
该我们了  咱们尖端科研实验室见
Uh, we're up. We'll meet you back at S.T.A.R. Labs
我们尽快过去
as soon as we can.
爱瑞丝  如果蝉看到了那文章
Iris, if Cicada sees that post--
他可能会选诺拉做下一个目标
Yeah, he may pick Nora as his next target.
好吧  你把我们带到了
Well, you have brought us to the location
你第一次遇到蝉的地点
you first encountered Cicada.
没错  你怎么知道的
That's right. How did you know that?
我什么都知道  我是侦探大师
I know everything. I'm a master detective.
我看过巴里·艾伦的调查文件
Look, I looked at the CSI file of Barry Allen.
没找到蝉的DNA样本  对吗
There is no evidence of Cicada DNA, right?
此外  看看这个地方  好吗
And moreover, look at this location, right?
交通这么繁忙
All the traffic through here--
你从这里找不到DNA证据
you can never pull DNA from here.
幸好我们来这里不是为了找DNA
It's a good thing we're not here for DNA.
那我们来这里做什么
What we are here for, then?
我们是要来调查蝉为什么戴那个面具
We're here to find out why Cicada wears that mask.
又是那个面具
Oh, encore with the mask!
你觉得他是对新鲜空气过敏吗
Do you think he's allergic to fresh air?
-不是  -没错  他戴面具是有原因的
- No. - No, he wears that mask for a reason.
好吧  你看  我抓住蝉37次了
All right, look, 37 times I've caught Cicada.
没有一次  那面具可以作为
Not once, not one time was the mask
-关键证据的  -是  这没错
- a key part of the evidence. - Yeah, that's true.
但你说这个蝉和其他的都不一样
But you said this Cicada is different than all the others,
所以为什么他的面具不会也不一样呢
so why wouldn't his mask be different, too?
也许那个面具只是...  你知道吗
Maybe it's just a mask to-You know what?
你想要从面具这个角度入手  请便
You want to pursuit mask angle, be my guest.
你想在这里找什么
What do you expect to find here?
当我被揍的时候
When I was getting my ass kicked,
我发现他越是用力
I noticed that the more he exerted himself,
他的呼吸就越沉重
the heavier his breathing got.
-谁都是这样  -所以我想...
- That's what happens. - So, I thought...
如果其中一次呼气足够重
if one of those breaths was strong enough...
我们或许能碰上大运
We might just get lucky.
我们碰什么大运
How we are going to get lucky?
巴里在这里找到了含氟聚合物的痕迹
Barry found traces of fluoropolymers here.
-所以呢  -所以网上说
- So? - So the Internet told me
他们很容易剥落
they're prone to flaking.
我是来找它们的
I'm here to get some of them.
网上有没有让你去污染犯罪现场
The Internet also tell you to contaminate your crime scene?
非常棒  侦探大师
Very good, master detective.
工业防毒面具
Turns out industrial respirators use
在鼻孔部位用的保护涂层
a protective coating around the nostrils
就是这个做的
that are made from this.
它接触到另一种化合物
And when this exposed to another compound,
硫酸二甲酯  含氟聚合物就会发出
dimethyl sulfate, fluoropolymers tend to emit
一种明显的臭味
a very distinct odor
烧焦的洋葱味
Burnt onions.
对
Right.
我们找到使用它的地方
We find out where this is used,
就能找到要找的人
we're going to find our man.
-基本常识  -基本演绎法
- Elementary. - Elementary.
才不是呢  夏洛克
No shrap, Sherlock.
是歇洛克
It's Sherloque.
斯宾塞
Spencer?
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West, wow.
好久不见  你怎么样
Long time. How are you?
是啊  我挺好  你呢
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'm good. And you?
挺好  你跟之前谈的那个犯罪现场鉴证员结婚了
Good. Married that CSI guy you were dating, huh?
是的
Uh, yeah.
-有小孩了吗  -没  不...
- Any kids yet? - Um, no. Not--
没有
No.
我也像你一样
You know, I followed your lead.
开了自己的博客  离开了《中城时报》
Started my own blog, left CCPN.
我们现在都是女版查尔斯·福斯特·凯恩了
Now we are both Charleine Foster Kanes.
电影《公民凯恩》主角  报业大亨
挺好
Right.
对了  你关于迪沃教授的报道  相当不错
BTdubs, those Professor DeVoe stories--respect.
超能力者现在很赚点击率啊
Metas are clickbait right now, right?
其实  我找你就是想谈这个
Yes, which is why I wanted to talk to you, actually,
当然了  是私底下谈
off the record, of course.
行啊  怎么了
Yeah, for sure. What's up?
最近有人给我提供消息说
So, uh, I recently found a source who thinks
超能力者被盯上了
that metas are being targeted.
有意思  被谁啊
Ooh, juicy. Who?
没人知道  连中城警局都不知道
Well, no one knows, not even CCPD.
但那些超能力者  包括极速者在内
But these metas, including speedsters
闪电侠和XS他们都有危险
like The Flash and XS, they are all in danger.
XS  那新来的女极速者都有代号了啊
XS. That new lady speedster has a code name.
跟她身材还真搭
Oh, like her size!
超小号
Right, extra small.
-代号是你取的吗  -不是
- Did you coin that? - No, no.
重点是  写关于XS的文章
Look, the point is, writing articles about XS
会让她成为目标
could make her a target.
也能让她出名
Or it could make her famous.
人们已经迷上她了...
I mean, people are already obsessed with her...
更迷我的应用程序
and my app even more.
再说了  你以前也没因为一点威胁
Besides, a little threat never stopped you
就不写闪电侠了
from writing about The Flash back in the day.
那不一样
That was different.
因为那是你的博客吗
Because it was your blog?
怎么  要听你的话  又不能学你吗
What--do as I say, not as I do?
听着  不要再写了行吗  趁没有人受伤
Look, please stop, okay? Before someone gets hurt.
会受伤的人只有你
The only one who's going to get hurt is you
到时我会让你的博客无人问津
when I make your blog irrelevant.
这是干什么  艾伦
What is this for, Allen?
只是找点答案  乔西
Just trying to get some answers, Jonesy.
你能把它发给凯特琳吗
Would you send that to Caitlin?
我知道的都告诉大家了  我什么都不知道
I told everyone everything I know, which is nothing.
-你什么都不记得了  -不记得
- You don't remember a thing? - No.
我发誓  艾伦  我只记得醒来
Okay, God's own truth, Allen-- all I remember is waking up,
为比赛做准备  离开家
getting ready for the game, leaving my house,
然后我只记得在赛场上醒来
and the next thing I know, I wake up in the field
那炸弹就爆炸了
after that bomb went off.
我上哪去弄个炸弹来
I mean, where would I even get a bomb?
拘留所里有证据
The evidence lockup.
炸弹是詹森·莫雷蒂案中缴获的库存
It was part of the inventory we seized from the Jansen-Moretti case.
拘留所里的摄像头拍到
The cameras in the lockup show you stuffing that bomb
你今早把炸弹塞到背包里
in your backpack this morning.
-乔  没有人受伤  -差点就有了
- Joe, no one got hurt. - They could've.
我的爱人  我的孩子... 你差点杀死她们
The woman I love, my baby-- you could've killed them.
我看着你过来的
I watched you come up, man.
对不起  乔...
I'm sorry, Joe...
但我发誓  我不知道怎么回事
but I swear, I don't know how this happened.
快  快
Move, move!
-我们有几个人  -发生什么了
- How many we got? - Hey, what is it?
《中城时报》着火  先遣急救员赶不过来
Fire at CCPN. First responders are across town.
我们走
We got to go.
图片新闻
总算来了
Finally.
大楼里的人已经疏散完毕
Okay, the building's already been evacuated.
消防车在来的路上
Fire trucks are on their way.
那我们进去  然后把火灭了
Okay, let's just get inside and put the fire out.
我从来没干过这个
I've never done this before.
快呀  行动起来啊
Come on. Seriously, move!
没关系  我们只要创造出真空
That's okay. We're just going to create a vacuum.
中城剧院
当代芭蕾之夜
行吧  我来让你行动起来
Fine. I will make you move.
享受这条新闻吧  闪电侠
Enjoy this news, Flash.
闪电侠现身
拉斯维加斯
行  我带你走过去  我们一进去...
All right, I'll walk you through it. Once we're inside--
闪电侠现身
拉斯维加斯
怎么  你... 你去哪里
What? Where-- where are you going?
-诺拉  怎么回事  -他就突然跑走了
- Nora, what's wrong? - He just ran away and left.
他战衣的定位显示他往西去了  一直往西
His suit's GPS has him west, way west.
巴里  巴里
Barry? Barry.
他听不见
He's not listening.
各位  我要怎么做
Guys, what do I do here?
诺拉  你要靠自己了
Okay, Nora, you're going to have to do this by yourself.
好吗  但是我会帮你
Okay? But I'm going to help you.
好的
Okay.
你得到大火中心
Okay, you need to get to the heart of the fire
从那里把火熄灭
and extinguish it from there.
-我到了  -小幅度转动你的手臂
- I got it. - Rotate your arms in tight circles.
两只手以相反方向转动
You need to move them in opposite directions,
制造两个真空
creating twin vacuums.
加油  诺拉
Come on, Nora.
爸爸已经这样做过无数次了
Dad's done this a thousand times.
你能做到
You can do this.
我成功了
I'm doing it!
继续
Keep going.
干得漂亮  诺拉
Great job, Nora.
谢谢  妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
你找到爸爸了吗
Hey--hey, did you find Dad?
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell?
我很高兴你在那里把火熄灭了
I'm glad you were there to put that out.
-事情可能会更严重  -谢谢  爸爸
- It could've been a lot worse. - Thanks, Dad.
别谢我  是你妈妈帮了你
Don't thank me. Your mom walked you through it.
你做得非常棒
You were really great out there.
你的扫描显示了一些奇怪的活动
So there was some weird activity with your scan,
但看上去一切都很正常
but everything looks fine.
你能记得的最后一件事是什么
What's the last thing you remember?
和诺拉一起站在中城时报大楼外面
Standing outside CCPN with Nora.
接下来我就在维加斯了
Next thing I know, I'm in Vegas.
我和琼斯警官身上发生了同样的事
That's exactly what happened to me and Officer Jones.
也许这种反常活动
So maybe the abnormal activity
是某种催眠诱导
was some sort of hypnotic induction?
我不知道  我认为如果有人试图催眠我
I don't know. I mean, I feel like one of us would've noticed
会有人注意到的
somebody trying to hypnotize me.
为什么会有人催眠我们去救人
Yeah, and why would someone hypnotize us to save people?
为了出名
Publicity.
斯宾塞·扬想通过让你出名而成名
Spencer Young wants to get famous by making you famous.
你怎么知道
You don't know that.
我们聊天的时候她承认的
She admitted it when we talked.
你为什么会和她聊天
Why would you go talk to her?
等等  看这条新闻的发布时间
Hold on, look at the timestamp on the post.
[未来属于女性 中城的女极速者]
下午7点52  那时我和诺拉跟乔西在一起
7:52 p.m.? Nora and I were still with Jonesy,
而且中城时报还没有引发火警
and the fire at CCPN hadn't even been reported yet.
我猜如果是你制造了新闻
I guess you'll always be the first one to the scoop
你就总能最先得到独家消息
if you're the one making it.
所以她是创造新闻版的《明日新闻》超能力者
So she's some sort of early edition meta who creates stories?
把假新闻提升到了新的水平
Fake news taken to a whole new level.
也许她是能预知新闻的通灵超能力者
Maybe she's some kind of meta psychic who predicts the news.
这还是不能证明她催眠了我们
That still doesn't mean she hypnotized us.
是啊
Yeah.
凯特琳  你能下载诺拉战衣上的
Caitlin, can you download the cortical biometrics
皮质生物特征  并和我的扫描对比吗
from Nora's suit and run it against my scans?
-马上去做  -多谢
- On it. - Thanks.
你有什么想法
What are you thinking?
我们得查出斯宾塞是不是幕后黑手
We need to figure out if Spencer's responsible for this.
[斯雷克化工厂]
我用谷歌成功找到了蝉的面具来自哪里
Google for the win on finding out where Cicada's mask is from.
谷歌大法好
Google for the win.
所以你认为这里是蝉的藏身处吗
So you think Cicada's hiding out here,
他就躲在这些门后面
just lurking behind those doors.
事实上我正是这样想的
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I do,
因为我的调查显示斯雷克化工厂
because my search also told me that Szrek Chemicals
大部分产品中都含有硫酸二甲酯
uses dimethyl sulfates in most of their products.
猜猜怎么样  我要抓住蝉
So guess what. I'm gonna take down Cicada.
好吧  我们会看到的  长颈鹿
Oh, well, we shall see, giraffe.
有什么能帮忙的吗
May I help you?
-你好  我是...  -伸缩人  我知道
- Hi, how are you? I'm-- - Elongated Man. I know.
歇洛克·威尔斯  大师级侦探
Sherloque Wells, yes, master detective.
我们等下再给你签名  我们有正事要办
You know, we'll sign autographs later-- we have some business.
想知道我们能否问你几个问题
We just want to know if we can ask you some questions, please.
关于什么
About?
我们的面具怎么了
What about our masks?
你有员工戴这样的面具吗
Do any of your employees wear them?
跟我来
Follow me.
每一家工厂的每一个工人都戴这个面具
Yep. Every worker, every plant wears one.
有多少家工厂
How many plants?
中城和楔石城有三家
Three in Central City and Keystone.
中西部有14家
14 in the Midwest alone.
所以大概有几千名工人
So probably thousands?
而且我们不是唯一用这种面具的工厂
Yeah, and we're not the only facility that uses them.
谢谢您
Thank you for your time.
我...
Hey, I, uh...
我特喜欢你前几周那个梨形梗
Love that pear meme going around the last few weeks.
太经典了
Classic.
经典  我有个建议
Classic. I have a suggestion for you.
下一次你用谷歌搜索的时候  看看第二页
Maybe the next time you do a Google search, advance to page two.
这是超能力手表  按下这个按钮
So here's the meta-watch, press that button.
如果斯宾塞是超能力者  它就会响
If Spencer's a meta, it'll beep.
如果她真的是超能力者
And if she's meta...
说明她可能很危险  所以马上回来
It means she could be dangerous, so come right back.
对  我们中的一个应该和你一起去
Yes. One of us would go with you,
但是她认识我和你爸  所以...
but she knows both me and your dad, so...
交给我吧
I got it.
如果你需要我们  我们就在这里
Okay, we're here if you need us, all ri--
我看见她了
I see her.
你要做的是走到离她五步以内
All you need to do is get within five feet of her,
按下按钮  然后出来
hit the button, in and out.
我知道
I know!
你明白我的意思了吗
You see what I mean?
前进半步  后退六步
Half-step forward, six steps back?
但上次救火你们表现得不错
I mean, you guys did great with the fire, though.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你应该把其中一种饮品
You should totally name one of your drinks
以最新的女性极速者XS命名
after that new female speedster, XS.
抱歉  斯宾塞
Hi. Sorry, Spencer.
没关系  我认识你吗
That's okay. Do I know you?
诺拉
Nora...
你要按下按钮
you have to press the button.
不  你不认识我
No. No, you don't know me.
但是你认识我
But you know me.
是的  抱歉  你是斯宾塞·扬
Yes, I do. sorry. You're Spencer Young.
你的斯宾谍网上每篇我都看
I read all your stuff on Spyn Zone.
那真是个不错的软件
It's a really good app.
完美的故事配上华丽的文笔
It's fantastic stories and really good writing.
我是你的大粉丝
I'm a--I'm a really big fan.
-诺拉  -我很喜欢和粉丝聊天
- Nora.. - I always enjoy meeting a fan.
尤其是像你这么可爱的粉丝
Especially when they're as adorable as you.
这是在干什么
What's happening?
她在和我们的女儿调情  我马上回来
She's flirting with our daughter. I'll be back.
-什么  -你坚守阵地
- What? - Hold down the fort.
爱瑞丝  等等
Iris, wait.
-你叫什么啊  -诺拉
- Do you have a name? - Nora, hey.
等等  你认识她吗
Wait, y-you know her?
我认识  她其实是...
I do. Well, she's actually--
其实她是...
This is, actually--
你看一眼你的表
Did you want to check your watch?
我觉得我们有一点晚了
I think we're running a little bit late.
-确实  -好的
- Right, yes. - Yeah.
检查超能力者中
好吧  我要走了
All right, well, I'm going to peace out.
未发现超能力者
但是我希望日后能见到可爱的你
But I hope to meet cute you again sometime.
诺拉
Nora.
看来她不是超能力者
Well, I guess she's not meta.
我想不是
I guess not.
不  不行  不行
Oh, no. No, no, no.
诺拉  我不管你觉不觉得她可爱
Nora--look, I don't care that you think she's cute.
她很危险  你要离她远一点
She's dangerous, okay? You need to stay away from her.
只是可能而已
She could be dangerous.
诺拉  我是想保护你
Nora, I am trying to protect you here.
你这一辈子不都是这样
Has that been your thing my whole life?
你说这话什么意思
What does that even mean, honestly?
这是你对我态度冷淡的原因吗
I mean, is that why you've been so cold to me,
这是你不想待在我身边的原因吗
why you don't want to spend any time with me?
我只是想更了解你一点
I'm -- I'm just trying to get to know you.
-别说了  -诺拉  我不明白
- Just drop it. - Nora, I don't under--
你欺骗了我
Look, you lied to me!
我从来不会欺骗你
I would never lie to you.
是吗  那这个你怎么解释
Yeah? What do you call that?
你在我体内植入一枚超能力抑制芯片
You put a power-dampening chip inside me
来夺走我的速度
to take away my speed.
在六个月之前
And until six months ago,
我都不知道我有超能力
I didn't even know I had powers.
我的一生就是个谎言
My whole life has been a lie
只因为"你想保护我"
because you have been trying to protect me.
我告诉你  我不需要你这么做
Well, guess what. I don't need you to do that.
呼叫被屏蔽
-你在做什么  -诺拉屏蔽了我
- What you doing? - Well, Nora blocked me.
所以我试着用量子计算机
So I'm trying to use the quantum computer
黑进她的电话  强制她接收我的来电
to access her phone and force her to accept my calls.
但我不是...
But I am no...
黑客
hacker.
你不觉得你这么做有点极端吗
Don't you think that's a little extreme?
是的巴里  不仅极端  还疯狂  还绝望
Yes, Barry, it's very extreme...and crazy and desperate,
但我现在极端疯狂绝望  好吗
but I am feeling extremely crazy and desperate, okay?
我本以为给她私人空间
I thought giving her space would, you know,
最终会让她恢复原样
have her eventually come around,
但原来她不是问题所在  我是
but it turns out she's not the problem. I am.
我不知道为什么我会
I mean, I don't know how I could do something
对她做出那种事  巴里
like that to her, Barry.
爱瑞丝  你什么都没做
Iris, you didn't do anything to her.
你不能因为一件未来的你可能做的事
You can't blame yourself for something
而责怪自己
future-you might do.
我很自责  巴里  而且不是可能
Yes, I can, Barry, and it's not a might.
我确实抑制了女儿的超能力
I suppressed our daughter's powers.
我将她人生的一大部分隐藏了起来
I kept a huge part of who she was a secret for her entire life.
我干的
I did that.
她会原谅你的
Look, she'll forgive you.
如果我爸爸在粒子加速器爆炸之后
What if my dad did something like that to you
也对你做了这种事  你会怎么办
after the particle accelerator exploded?
体会到了吧
See?
我不知道我当初怎么忍心对她做这种事
I don't understand how I could do something like that to her.
我不知道你为什么做
Look, I don't know why you do it,
我也不需要知道
but I don't need to.
我知道你为家里做的一切都是出于爱
I know that anything you do for our family, it's out of love.
所以  不管你当初做这件事的原因是什么
So, whatever reason future-you has for doing this,
我相信这是正确的选择
I have faith that it's the right thing to do,
你也应该如此
and so should you.
可是  我还是很难相信
Yeah, well, I'm having a really hard time believing that.
我对你的信心足够咱们俩用了
Well, then it's a good thing I have enough faith in you
这样就好了
for the both of us.
好吧
All right?
这个太不寻常了
That's unusual.
斯诺博士
Dr. Snow.
Oh, Dr. Snow.
我吓到你了  斯诺博士
I have frightened you, Dr. Snow.
我猜你来这的目的不是为了杀死我吧
I assume you came here for some other reason than murdering me?
我的天
Oh, dear God.
如果我是来杀你的  斯诺博士
If I was to murder you, Dr. Snow,
我怎么会用这么明显的方式
I would not do it in such an obvious fashion.
听着  对于蝉的身份  我有个假想
Look, I have a theory on the identity of Cicada.
我需要你的协助
I request your assistance.
这样啊  我快做完了
Uh, okay. I was just finishing up.
不是你的专业知识  只是协助
Not your expertise, your assistance.
我要你朝我的胸口打一拳
I need you to punch me in the chest.
什么
What?
朝这  在这封个膜上面  应该怎么说
Right here, above the--um, dee-aphragm. How do you say?
横膈膜
Diaphragm?
横膈膜  对
Diaphragm, right.
对着腹腔神经丛用全力打  来吧
In the solar plexus as hard as you can. Allé.
听着  夏洛克
Listen, Sherlock--
歇洛克
Loque.
这就是那种所谓的
So this is one of those things
君子动口不动手吗
where you are just the brains and not the brawn?
你没有胆量  你没有勇气
You don't have the guts. You lack the courage.
你太逊了
You're soft.
很有可能你都打不到这个点上
Probably you couldn't even hit me in the spot.
强调一点  我知道你刚才在干什么
For the record, I know what you just did.
-然后呢  -然后奏效了
And? And it worked.
太好了  那就  开始吧
Très bien. Then... allé.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你听起来就像...
You sound just like...
蝉
Cicada.
中城体育场
什么情况
What do we got?
中城警局的电话被
CCPD is getting bombarded with calls from people
从中城体育场观看橄榄球比赛的人打爆了
at the soccer game at Central City Stadium.
新闻里也都是这个
It's all over the news, too.
好的  我这就过去
Okay, I'm going to get over there.
中城警局已经把体育场清空了
CCPD already cleared out the stadium.
找到炸弹  我们来帮着拆除
Find the bomb, and we'll help you disarm it.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我路上告诉你吧  来吧
I'll tell you on the way.Come on.
-没发现  你呢  -没有
- Nothing, you? - No.
爱瑞丝  没有炸弹
Iris, there's no bomb.
中城体育场橄榄球比赛中出现炸弹威胁
你们看斯宾塞帖子上的时间标记
Guys, look at the timestamp on Spencer's post.
上午十一点零五分
11: 05 A.M.
对  再看看中城警局接到的
Yeah, and now look at the time that CCPD
第一个报告看见炸弹的电话的时间
got the first call about the bomb sighting.
中城警局
电话记录
是五分钟之后
It was five minutes later.
你能把琼斯警官脑部扫描调出来吗
Hey, can you bring up Officer Jones' brain scan?
我来把斯宾塞帖子的代码
I'm going to run the code
用反编译工具跑一下
of Spencer's post through the decompiler.
我们看看下面有什么
Let's see what's underneath.
有了
Got it.
-完成  -脑部扫描  代码完全一致
- Done. - The brain scan. The code is an exact match.
XS杀死闪电侠
-巴里  是标题  -什么
- Barry, it's the headlines. - What?
这就是斯宾塞催眠人们的方法
That's how Spencer's hypnotizing people.
他们看她的标题  千万不要看
They're reading her headlines! Don't look at them.
太晚了
Too late!
诺拉被催眠了
Nora's been hypnotized.
她想要杀了我
She's trying to kill me.
诺拉  你得打破这状态
Nora, you got to snap out of this.
我得要杀了你
What I have to do is kill you.
凯特琳  你接手
Caitlin, take over.
-你要去哪里  -去把我的家人救回来
- Where are you going? - To get my family back.
快点  赶紧把他干掉
Hurry up and kill him already.
该闪了
Time to bounce.
你会没事的
Hey, you're going to be okay. All right?
射得好
Nice shot!
伙计们  我们知道斯宾塞在哪里吗
Guys, do we know where Spencer is?
我没办法定位她的手机
I can't ping her phone.
为了防止遥控引爆炸弹
CCPD disabled all the cell towers
中城警局把这区域所有基站都关了
in the area to prevent a remote bomb detonation.
为了把那些标题打到大屏幕上
She must be local in order to put those headlines
她就必须在现场  对吗
up on that big screen, right?
-她在体育场  -她就在这
- She's at the stadium. - She's here.
看起来你得要换个地方编故事了
Looks like you'll be trading this cell in for another.
[范布伦市长辞职]
斯宾塞被关进铁山监狱了
All right, Spencer's all locked up in Iron Heights.
-市长辞职了  -什么
- The Mayor's resigning. - What?
她能待这么久我已经很吃惊了
I'm surprised she lasted this long.
幸运的是  我给我的文章搞到了她
Luckily, I was able to get a quote from her
赦免琼斯警官的话
exonerating Officer Jones for my article.
帖子明天发布
Post will go up tomorrow.
知道他的朋友没事乔爷爷会宽慰的
Papa Joe will be relieved his friend's in the clear.
是啊
Yeah.
斯宾塞的事已经过去了  至少我们可以
Well, at least now, with Spencer behind us,
集中精力对付大鱼了
we can concentrate on bigger fish.
是的
Yes, we can.
-所以  -夏洛克
- So... - Uh, Sherlock--
-歇洛克  -他认为他找到辨识蝉身份的方法
- Sherloque. - He thinks he's found a key to Cicada's identity.
一个帮助我们解决疑惑的重要线索
A crucial clue to help us solve our little mystery.
我们都知道由于面具里的呼吸器
So we all know the distinctive sound of Cicada's breathing
蝉呼吸时会发出独特声音
due to the respirator in the mask.
但除此之外  原因还有他肺部的损伤
But not just that, because also his lungs are injured.
那是什么造成的损伤
But injured from what?
以往  有一个意外总会导致大卫·赫希
Historically, there is an event that causes David Hersch
成为蝉  但这次是例外
to always become Cicada, but not this time.
这是一个不同的蝉  因为
There's a different Cicada because--
因为诺拉帮助我摧毁了卫星
Because Nora helped me destroy the satellite.
艾伦先生  诺拉打击卫星
Monsieur Allen, Nora's strike through the satellite
造成残骸轨迹的改变
changed the trajectory of the debris,
而新的残骸击伤了另一个人
and now the debris has hit a new person and injured...
我们的新蝉
our new Cicada.
好吧  但这怎么会赋予他超能力
Okay, but how did that give him his powers?
迪沃用暗物质浸泡卫星
DeVoe flooded the satellite with dark matter.
残骸会充满暗物质是很合理的
It makes sense that the pieces would be saturated.
所以蝉和他的匕首是在
So Cicada and the dagger were created
大悟之道当晚诞生的
the night of the Enlightenment.
同时获得力量
Acquired powers together.
听着  夏洛克
Well, listen, Sherloke--
-歇洛克  -我必须跟你说
- Sherloque. - I got to hand it to you.
这真是令人敬佩
That's very impressive.
重大的突破  对吧  德比先生
It's quite a breakthrough, right, Monsieur Dibny?
这无法归功于我
One that I cannot take any credit for.
不  所有的功劳与赞扬
No, all the credit, all the praise
都是属于你的  德比先生
goes to you, Monsieur Dibny.
是你直觉要追查面具的  对吧
It was your instincts to follow the mask, right?
你是正确的  而我...
Well, you were right, and I was...
没那么正确
less right.
我道歉
I apologize.
好吧  大家  我很抱歉
Okay, guys, I'm sorry.
匕首的那部分依旧不合理
The dagger part still doesn't make sense.
我是说  物体不能变成超能物  对吧
I mean, things cannot become metas, right?
那我就不确定了
I don't know about that.
卫星不只是创造了新的超能力者
Our satellite didn't just create new metas.
它还创造了超能科技
It created meta-tech.
这样一来超能力者的能力将能够...
Which puts meta-human abilities in the hands of...
被任何人使用
anyone.
凯特琳说你会没事的
Caitlin says you're going to be fine.
我很抱歉我抑制了你的能力  但是
I'm sorry for suppressing your powers, but...
我认为那是正确的做法
I think it was the right thing to do.
不  我  我
Yeah. No, I-I...
我理解  我是说  我试着要杀爸爸
I get it. I mean, I was trying to kill Dad.
我会做出跟你一样的选择
I would've done the same thing, too.
不  那...
No, that's...
那不是我的意思
That's not what I mean.
我是在说未来
I'm talking about in the future.
什么
What?
我知道你既沮丧又愤怒
I know that you're upset and angry.
而诚实地说  我...
And honestly, I...
在今天以前  我甚至无法想象出一个
Before today, I couldn't even imagine a situation
我会对你做出那样事情的情况
where I would do something like that to you.
但在我经历刚刚的情况后
But after seeing the choice that I just made...
我知道不论是什么理由让我
I know that whatever reason I would have
向你保密你的超能力
for keeping your powers a secret, it...
那必定是一个充分的理由  诺拉
it must have been a good one, Nora.
那必定是为了保护你
It must have been to protect you.
不
No.
今天所发生的事
What happened today...
跟未来所发生的一点关系也没有
has nothing to do with what happens in the future.
你不是因为我被洗脑或是攻击人们
You didn't suppress my abilities my whole life
而抑制我的超能力
because I was brainwashed or attacking people.
你是为了控制我
You did it to control me.
我一生都感觉我与其他人不同
My whole life I felt like I was different
但我不知道原因
than everybody else, but I didn't know why.
你拿走一个我的选择
You took a choice away from me
而我甚至不知道我有
that I didn't even know that I had...
一个像我父亲一样成为英雄的选择
A choice to be a hero, like my dad.
怎么回事
What's going on?
-没什么  我们只是在说活  -不对
- Nothing, we're just talking. - No.
妈妈认为她在未来有一个充分的理由
Mom thinks that she had good reason to suppress my powers
来抑制我的超能力  但她还不知道是什么
in the future, but she doesn't know what that reason is.
我敢肯定是个好理由
I'm sure it's a good one.
诺拉  我不用到未来
Look, Nora, I don't have to visit the future
来知道爱瑞丝将会成为怎样的母亲
to know what kind of mother Iris's gonna be.
她是我所认识的人里面最重视家庭的
She cares about family more than anyone I've ever met.
好吗  还有
Okay? And...
我支持她的决定
I support her decisions...
过去的  现在的  未来的
past, present, and future.
那么我猜我应该重新思考家庭的意义
Then I guess I need to rethink what the meaning of family is.
等等  诺拉
Nora, wait.
你知道我得知我有超能力时最难过什么吗
Do you know what hurt the most about learning I had powers?
不是从我妈妈那知道的
Not hearing it from my mom.
没事的
It's all right.
-你好  -你好  诺拉
- Hi. - Nora, hi.
说来话长
Um, it's kind of a long story,
但我可以待在这吗
but can I stay here?
进来吧  孩子
Get in here, kid.
你确定这不会太麻烦你
Are you sure it's not too much trouble?
没关系  也许等会再说原因
It's fine. Maybe talk about the reason later?
但现在  楼上有干净的枕头和毯子
But for now, there's some fresh pillows and blankets upstairs.
谢谢  乔爷爷
Thanks, Papa Joe.